

🛘 (+92) 3365540465 | 🔀 azharmalikdanial@gmail.com | 🏕 malikdanial.xyz | 🖸 its-Danial | 🛅 malik-danial-azhar

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Skills

Programming Languages JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, Bash

Human Languages English, Urdu, Chinese

Technologies React. js, React Native, Next. js, Vue. js, Node. js, Express. js, Spring Boot/Cloud, FastAPI, Tensorflow, PyTorch

Databases: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Redis

Platforms/Tools: Heroku, Vercel, Docker, Linux, JetBrains, Visual Studio, GIT, IPython

Summary_

Enthusiastic and results-driven software engineer with a diverse international background, originally from Islamabad, Pakistan, and recently graduated in China. Currently employed as a Software Engineering I at Bayt.com, where I specialize in Vue.js 2. I am actively leading the migration of projects to the latest versions and technologies, demonstrating a strong commitment to staying current in the ever-evolving software landscape.

Work Experience _____

Bayt.comDubai, UAE · Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER I

Sept. 2023 - Present

- Key contributor in the Evalufy department, specializing in the development of Evalufy an online platform for conducting interviews, exams, surveys, and more.
- Lead role in the migration of the front-end technology stack from Vue. js 2 to the latest Vue. js and Vite version, implementing cutting-edge features to enhance user experience.
- Currently engaged in developing and implementing new features in response to the growing demand for online evaluation tools, particularly in the post-COVID era.
- Collaborating seamlessly with cross-functional teams, ensuring effective communication and synergy between front-end and back-end development efforts.
- Working with Spring Flow to streamline and optimize the back-end processes, contributing to the overall efficiency of the Evalufy platform.
- Adhering to best practices in software development, including version control and collaborative coding on platforms such as GitLab and Jira

NeusoftShenyang, China

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

May. 2022 - Jul. 2022

- Developed a full-stack E-Learning platform called WebAcademy, which allows teachers to publish courses and users (students) to purchase them and track their learning progress.
- Worked primarily on the front-end writing 43,000+ lines, using React.js 18 Typescript, React Router Dom, React Query, Redux, Tailwind CSS, and MaterialUI.
- Collaborated with team to develop back-end using Spring Cloud Alibaba.
- · Contributed to the system architecture design, database structures, and its implementation using MySQL and Spring Data JPA.
- Learned how to collaborate on large-scale projects and contribute through GitHub.

Jolta Technology DMCC

Islamabad, Pakistan Jun. 2016 - Jul. 2016

GAME DEVELOPER INTER

- Developed fundamental C# and Unity skills
- Learned to present various Mini-game ideas and proposals
- Developed a complete Flappy Bird game clone
- · Learned to work with a schedule and strict time frame.

Education

Northeastern University (CN)

Shenyang, China

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

• 3.56 GPA

Personal Projects

RealEnvision real-envision.vercel.app

- The design and implementation of an image-generation system based on Diffusion model.
- The system offers users various different image generation and modification tools such as text-to-image, image-to-image, image inpainting, and super-resolution.
- · Authenticated users can save and manage generated images as projects for future reusability and further modifications.
- · Made using React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, MongoDB, OAuth, TailwindCSS, Python FastAPI, HuggingFace, PyTorch

WatchedThis watched-this.vercel.app

- An application to get the popular, trending movies and TV Shows using TheMovieDB API.
- · Allows users to track watched TV show Episodes and get information on the latest episodes such as release dates.
- Made using NextJS Typescirpt, MongoDB, OAuth, TailwindCSS

MyPlaces GitHub Link

- IOS and Android application to save details about your favorite traveled places such as pictures, map location, etc.
 Made using React Native Typescript, Expo, Google Location API, SQLite, NativeWind, Native Camera API, React Navigation, Geoapify API, and
- Google+Apple Maps

SharedExpense GitHub Link

- IOS and Android application to track monthly shared expenses such as those with a roommate
- Made using React Native Typescript, Expo, SQLite, NativeWind, React Navigation

Penny Juice Website Redesign

penny-juice-redesign.vercel.app

- · My design and take on the famous penny juice website, to improve human computer interaction and design skills
- Made using Next.js, TailwindCSS, FramerMotion

Neusoft Cloud Factory GitHub Link

- Application to manage, maintain and monitor factory machinery and equipment.
- Deigned with Figma, made using React.js, Material UI and Recharts
- Completely responsive and screen-reader ready.